

Paulo Lopes da Silva Physicist (M. Sc.)

- São José do Egito PE Brazil
- Brazilian
- unmarried

Skills

Software development	6+ yrs.
Computer programming/ Linux/Windowsy	10+ yrs.
Internet business/ E-commerce	4+ yrs.
Web development	2+ yrs.
Big data/ Data Science/ Data science	2+ yrs.
Python and C++ technology	2+ yrs.
Internet of things	1+ yrs.
Cloud computing	1+ yrs.
German	L1
English	C1

Biography

I have an experimental background working on the CERN, the European Organization for Nuclear Research, Pierre Auger Collaboration and the KTeV Experiments at FERMILAB, USA. These three international collaborations were composed of many universities around the world, specially Europe, USA and Latin America. My work group on the NA48 - based in Germany and Switzerland - carry out on data analysis of this experiment. During 3 years I worked as a Ph.D candidate for the german group of the Johannes Gutenberg University as a fellow supported by the German Academic Exchange Program (DAAD). Since I concluded my fellowship in Germany I have been teaching courses of mathematics, statistics, physics, electronics and laboratory work at private colleges and universities in São Paulo and in João Pessoa, where I am living now. One of my academic tasks is to lead work groups of students into development of academic discussion or into the development and application of new technologies related with engineering and computer science and under the concept of StartUps e Fintechs. Recently, my focus on technologies has change towards modern concepts of Industrie 4.0, Internet of Things (IoT), Cloud Computer and Machine Learning. These are the base of a promising technology which tends to revolutionize and connect the global world via heterogeneous smart devices through seamless connectivity. Nowadays, I have interest in analyzing the impact of the IoT concept on the operations of modern organizations and the implementation of changes related to its use. The main areas of possibilities arising - not only in engineering - but also in other many basic types of emerging new business models are my object of studies and research.

Work experience

Assistant Professor

05/2020 - 03/2022

Eletronics Engineering Teclogists - High School João Pessoa, PB

Development of projets on informatic and eletronics.

Assistant Professor

08/2018 - 12/2020

Department of Engineering

Wyden/ADTALEM/Kroton/YDUCs Universities, João Pessoa, PB

Assistant Professor

06/2014 - 06/2017

Department of Engineering UNIPÊ Educational Center, João Pessoa, PB

Lectures on Physics, Computer Science and Mathematics.

Assistant Professor

02/2005 - 06/2013

Department of Engineering UNINOVE Educational Center São Paulo, SP

Lectures on Physics and Laboratory of Physics.

Assistant Professor

02/2003 - 02/2014

Department of Physics. Federal University of Paraiba, Campina Grande -PB

Lectures on Physics and Laboratory of Physics.

Education

03/1999 - 06/2002

Ph.D in Physics

Johannes Gutenberg University - Mainz, Germany

Particle Physics Field: "Messung Dalitz Zerfalls mit dem NA48 Detector".

07/1996 - 10/1998

Master Degee in Physics (M.Sc.)

University of São Paulo - Brazil

Nuclear Physics Master's thesis: "Detection of Gamma Ray Burst with the Pierre Auger Detector".

03/1992 - 06/1996

Graduation in Physics (Bachelor Degree)

University of São Paulo

Particle Physics Bachelor's dissertation: "Construction and test of a set of drift chambers for the KTeV Experiment at FERMILAB - USA".

Interests

- ▶ Tecnologies & Gadgets
- ▶ Fitness & Cooking
- ▶ Languages & Travel
- Philosophy

Contact

- Avenida Boa Viagem, 118, apt. 701 - Recife - PE - Brazil - 51011-000
- +55 81 99792 9940
- paul_opes_ilva@yahoo.com.br
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/paulo-lopes-da-silva-74936469

http://lattes.cnpq.br/ 1333159250664479

CERN, the European Organization for Nuclear

Research - Geneva, Switzerland

Fellowship at the Experimental Physics Division.

05/2004 - 10/2004

Scholarship

Ph.D

DAAD: German Academic Exchange Service

CERN: European Organization for Nuclear Research

Ms.C

CAPES: Coordenação de Aperfeiçoamento de Pessoal de Nível Superior

Master of Science in Physics

07/1996 - 06/1998

02/1993 - 06/1996

12/1998 - 06/2002

Graduation

CNPq: Conselho Nacional de Desenvolvimento Científico e Tecnológico

Bachelor of Science in Physics

Publications

- NA48 Collaboration. "A PRECISION MEASUREMENT OF DIRECT CP VIO-LATION IN THE DECAY OF NEUTRAL KAONS INTO TWO PIONS.". In: Phys.Lett.B544:97-112,2002.
- NA48 Collaboration. "A MEASUREMENT OF $k_s \longleftrightarrow \pi_0 \gamma \gamma$ THE LIFETIME". In: *Phys.Lett.B537:28-40,2002*.
- NA48 Collaboration. "A PRECISE MEASUREMENT OF THE DIRECT CP VIOLATION PARAMETER $Re^{\underline{e}\cdot}_{\epsilon}$ ". In: Eur.Phys.J.C22:231-254,2001.

Recife, 4th August 2022

Paulo Lopes da Silva